<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Product reviews on Curran D. Muhlberger</title>
    <link>http://www.muhlbergerweb.com/writing/product_reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Product reviews on Curran D. Muhlberger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 01:15:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.muhlbergerweb.com/writing/product_reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Photo gear</title>
      <link>http://www.muhlbergerweb.com/writing/product_reviews/photo_gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 01:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.muhlbergerweb.com/writing/product_reviews/photo_gear/</guid>
      <description>As a hobbyist whose experience is mostly limited to my own equipment, I’ll try to refrain from “reviews” based on a sample size of one. Instead, I’ll simply offer my comments on what gear I’ve chosen to buy and how it’s worked out for me.
Pentax K-x (entry-level DSLR) It was a great first DSLR. Small, high image quality, intermediate-level features, and the flexibility to use AA batteries. But its ergonomics don’t hold a candle to the K-5, and its plasticy build creaks a bit more with each passing year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pentax K-5 review</title>
      <link>http://www.muhlbergerweb.com/writing/product_reviews/pentax_k5_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.muhlbergerweb.com/writing/product_reviews/pentax_k5_review/</guid>
      <description>Simply one of the best APS-C DSLRs you can buy. The 14-bit sensor offers tremendous dynamic range, allowing raw files processed in Lightroom 4 to exhibit fantastic detail in all tonal regions. Judging from more technical reviews, it appears to offer the best image quality to be found short of full-frame. And Pentax’s ergonomics and user interfaces are always comfortable and intuitive, offering easy access to the controls you actually want.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
